<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sapling on</title><link>https://nategb.com/garden/tags/sapling/</link><description>Recent content in sapling on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://nategb.com/garden/tags/sapling/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Backups</title><link>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Backups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Backups/</guid><description>The practice of creating and storing copies of data in order to allow data restoration in the event of a failure or loss of the original data.</description></item><item><title>Data Loss Prevention</title><link>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Data-Loss-Prevention/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Data-Loss-Prevention/</guid><description>Keep that data safe Usually an automated tool Can protect [[Intellectual Property]] data Will usually consist of three components Policy Server to configure classification, confidentiality, and privacy rules and polices, log incidents, and compile reports Endpoint Agents to enforce policy on client computers, even when they are not connected to the network Network Agents to scan communications at network borders and interface with web and messaging servers to enforce policy DLP agents scan content in structured formats, like databases with a formal access control model DLP agents can also scan content in unstructured formats, like emails or word processing documents DLP agents can block the transfer of content if it does not conform to a predefined policy (Side note, this is probably what the Pope-blessed laptop used) Remediation The action a DLP software takes when it detects policy violation Alert only Block Quarantine Tombstone The file is quarantined and replaced with one describing the policy violation and how the user can release it again</description></item><item><title>Data Roles and Responsibilities</title><link>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Data-Roles-and-Responsibilities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Data-Roles-and-Responsibilities/</guid><description>A [[data governance]] policy describes the security controls that will be applied to protect data at each stage of its data life cycle.</description></item><item><title>Data Types</title><link>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Data-Types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Data-Types/</guid><description>A data type schema usually applies more detailed labels than Data Classification.
Personally Identifiable Information Data can be used to identify, contact, or locate and individual Several types of PII, including: SSN name date of birth email address telephone number street address biometric data Some information could be PII depending on context.</description></item><item><title>Database Deidentification Methods</title><link>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Database-Deidentification-Methods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Database-Deidentification-Methods/</guid><description>Deidentification methods are usually implemented as part of the database management system hosting the data. Sensitive fields will be tagged for deidentification whenever a query or report is run.</description></item><item><title>Incident Response Plan</title><link>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Incident-Response-Plan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Incident-Response-Plan/</guid><description>Incident Response Plan Lists the procedures, contacts, and resources available to responders for various incident categories CIRT responsible for developing profiles or scenarios of typical incidents (DDoS, virus/worm outbreak, data exfiltration by an external adversary, etc) These profiles guide investigators in determining priorities and remediation plans [[CIRT]] could also be responsible for making a [[Playbook]] Assess for Severity Each incident has to be assessed and prioritized to allocate resources efficiently.</description></item><item><title>Incident Response Process</title><link>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Incident-Response-Process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Incident-Response-Process/</guid><description>Defined by NIST 800.61r2, incident response follows a well-structure process. There are 6 principal stages in an incident response lifecycle.</description></item><item><title>Risk Management</title><link>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Risk-Management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Risk-Management/</guid><description>Risk management is the process for identifying, assessing, and mitigation vulnerabilities and threats to the essential functions that a business must perform to serve its customers There are 5 main phases to risk management:</description></item><item><title>Software Design Lifecycle</title><link>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Software-Development-Lifecycle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nategb.com/garden/notes/Software-Development-Lifecycle/</guid><description>There are 4 main phases to the software development lifecycle:
Analysis This is the practice of determining the goals for a program The &amp;ldquo;Why&amp;rdquo; Design Design determines the specifics of how to build a program The &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rdquo; Implementation Implementation builds the program according to the design The &amp;ldquo;How&amp;rdquo; Testing Testing checks that the program meets the goal There are 2 main methods of implementing the software development lifecycle: the [[notes/Waterfall Approach]] and the [[notes/Agile Approach]].</description></item></channel></rss>