<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Notes on</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/</link><description>Recent content in Notes on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://garden.nategb.com/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title/><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Annualized-Rate-of-Occurrence/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Annualized-Rate-of-Occurrence/</guid><description>n&amp;mdash; title: &amp;ldquo;Annualized Rate of Occurrence&amp;rdquo; tags:
seed security An expression of the Likelihood of a risk as the number of times per year a particular loss is expected to occur.</description></item><item><title>3-2-1 Rule</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/3-2-1-Rule/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/3-2-1-Rule/</guid><description>A data storage principle that states that your should have 3 copies of your data, across 2 media types, with one copy held offline and offsite.</description></item><item><title>Aggregation or Banding</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Aggregation-or-Banding/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Aggregation-or-Banding/</guid><description>Database Deidentification Methods that involve generalizing data to make it less specific, such as turning specific values into ranges</description></item><item><title>Agile Approach</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Agile-Approach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Agile-Approach/</guid><description>The Agile Approach involves developing and implementing code piece-by-piece on a continuous basis. It usually involves breaking up each task that a program should accomplish and tackling each one individually.</description></item><item><title>American Recovery and Reinvestment Act</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/American-Recovery-and-Reinvestment-Act/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/American-Recovery-and-Reinvestment-Act/</guid><description>A wide-ranging act passed in 2009 that authorized $787 billion in spending and tax cuts over a 10-year period. Title XIII includes strong privacy provisions for Electronic Health Records, banning the sale of health information and promoting the use of audit trails and encryption and providing rights of access for patients.</description></item><item><title>Annualized Loss Expectancy</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Annualized-Loss-Expectancy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Annualized-Loss-Expectancy/</guid><description>The amount that would be lost over the course of a year. Determined by multiplying the Single Loss Expectancy by the Annualized Rate of Occurrence</description></item><item><title>Backups</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Backups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Backups/</guid><description>The practice of creating and storing copies of data in order to allow data restoration in the event of a failure or loss of the original data.</description></item><item><title>Breach of Contract</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Breach-of-Contract/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Breach-of-Contract/</guid><description>When one party fails to meet the terms of a contract</description></item><item><title>Bribery</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Bribery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Bribery/</guid><description>Bribes are things given that are made in secret, indirectly through a third party, and encourage an obligation for the recipient to act favorably toward the donor</description></item><item><title>Business Case</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Business-Case/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Business-Case/</guid><description>A written document or report that helps executive management and key stakeholders determine the benefits and rewards of the Project. The elements of a Business Case include:</description></item><item><title>Call List</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Call-List/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Call-List/</guid><description>A document listing authorized contacts for notification and collaboration during a security incident.</description></item><item><title>Cash Flow Techniques</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Cash-Flow-Techniques/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Cash-Flow-Techniques/</guid><description>Provide data on the overall financials of the alternative solutions or projects. Each of these techniques rely on the concept of time value of money.</description></item><item><title>Chain of Custody</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Chain-of-Custody/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Chain-of-Custody/</guid><description>The record of evidence history from collection, to presentation in court, to disposal</description></item><item><title>CIA Triad</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/CIA-Triad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/CIA-Triad/</guid><description> Confidentiality The privacy and secrecy of a thing, AKA only accessible by authorized and authenticated users Integrity The data is ensured to be unaltered; it is exactly what it was, and all changes are authorized and audited Availability The data is accessible for those who need it and are allowed to access it</description></item><item><title>CIRT</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/CIRT/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/CIRT/</guid><description>Cyber Incident Response Team A dedicated team that acts as a single point-of-contact for the notification of security events.
Also know as Computer Security Incident Response Team (CSIRT) or Computer Emergency Response Team (CERT)</description></item><item><title>Clinical Decision Support</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Clinical-Decision-Support/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Clinical-Decision-Support/</guid><description>A process and a set of tolls designed to enhance healthcare-related decision making through the use of clinical knowledge and patient-specific information to improve healthcare delivery.</description></item><item><title>Closing</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Closing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Closing/</guid><description>The primary purpose of the closing phase is to validate deliverables and document the formal acceptance of the project work. Once that&amp;rsquo;s complete, a handoff occurs whereby the completed product or result of the project is turned over to the organization for ongoing maintenance and support.</description></item><item><title>Communication Plan</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Communication-Plan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Communication-Plan/</guid><description>A policy implemented to effectively communicate a security incident. The goal is to communicate to necessary parties only, to avoid alerting attackers as well.</description></item><item><title>Communications Decency Act</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Communications-Decency-Act/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Communications-Decency-Act/</guid><description>Part of the Telecommunications Act
Its primary purpose was to allow free competition among phone, cable, and TV companies. Title V is specifically aimed at protecting children from pornography.</description></item><item><title>Community Cloud</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Community-Cloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Community-Cloud/</guid><description>Community clouds are a type of cloud computing where the cloud is available to be used by a community. It can also be called a public cloud.</description></item><item><title>Conflict of Interest</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Conflict-of-Interest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Conflict-of-Interest/</guid><description>A conflict between someone&amp;rsquo;s self-interest and the client&amp;rsquo;s interest</description></item><item><title>Consequentialism</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Consequentialism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Consequentialism/</guid><description>The philosophy of weighing the morality of actions on the basis of their probably outcomes or consequences
See also: Utilitarianism</description></item><item><title>Corporate Code of Ethics</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Corporate-Code-of-Ethics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Corporate-Code-of-Ethics/</guid><description>A statement that highlights an organization&amp;rsquo;s key ethical issues and identifies the overarching values and principles that are important tot the organization and it&amp;rsquo;s decision making</description></item><item><title>Corporate social responsibility</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Corporate-social-responsibility/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Corporate-social-responsibility/</guid><description>The concept that an organization should act ethically by taking responsibility for the impact of its actions on its shareholders, consumers, employees, community, environment, and suppliers</description></item><item><title>Cost-Benefit Analysis</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Cost-Benefit-Analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Cost-Benefit-Analysis/</guid><description>Compares the cost to produce the product or service to the financial gain (or benefit) the organization stands to make as a result of executing the project.</description></item><item><title>Customer Data</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Customer-Data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Customer-Data/</guid><description>Data that could be used to identify a customer, like employees, sales, and technical support contacts.</description></item><item><title>Customer Relationship Management</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Customer-Relationship-Management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Customer-Relationship-Management/</guid><description>Software that helps businesses manage their relationships and interactions with their customers and future customers. CRMs aggregate data about the customer in one place and provide an efficient and practical way for the organization to interact with their customer.</description></item><item><title>Cyber Kill Chain</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Cyber-Kill-Chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Cyber-Kill-Chain/</guid><description>A framework that describes the stages of a cyber attack
Reconnaissance Scoping out the target Weaponization Preparation of attack based on recon from previous step Could be payload code + exploit code Delivery Weaponized code is transmitted to target system Exploitation Weaponized code is executed on the system Installation Weaponized code runs a remote access tool (RAT) and achieves persistence on target system Command and control Outbound channel is established to remote server that allows the attacker to control the RAT Actions on objectives Access is used to collect information and exfiltrate information from target There could be other goals or motives See Also: [[MITRE ATT&amp;amp;CK]] and [[Diamond Model]]</description></item><item><title>Data at Rest</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-at-Rest/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-at-Rest/</guid><description>Data is in some sort of persistent storage media
See also: Data in Transit and [[Data in Use]]</description></item><item><title>Data Classifications</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Classifications/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Classifications/</guid><description>Tags data so it can be managed through the Information Life Cycle A decision tree for applying one or more tags or labels to each data asset Tags usually based on the degree of confidentiality required Public (unclassified) No restrictions on viewing data No risk to organization if it is disclosed, but does pose a risk if it is modified or not available Confidential (secret) Information is highly sensitive, for viewing only by approved persons within the owner organization, and possibly by trusted third parties under [[NDA]] Critical (top secret) Information is too valuable to allow any risk of its capture.</description></item><item><title>Data Controller</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Controller/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Controller/</guid><description>Responsible for determining why and how data is stored, collected, and used and for ensuring that these purposes and means are lawful.</description></item><item><title>Data Custodian</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Custodian/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Custodian/</guid><description>Responsible for access control, encryption, and backup/recovery measures. Basically the guy who takes care of the hardware and storage aspect.</description></item><item><title>Data Disparity</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Disparity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Disparity/</guid><description>Data gaps or lags that misrepresent reality</description></item><item><title>Data Exfiltraion</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Exfiltraion/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Exfiltraion/</guid><description>Unauthorized copying or retrieval of data from a system.</description></item><item><title>Data in Transit</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-in-Transit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-in-Transit/</guid><description>Data that is being transmitted over a network actively. Also called data in motion,
See also: Data at Rest and [[Data in Use]]</description></item><item><title>Data in Use</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-in-Use/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-in-Use/</guid><description>Data present in volatile memory, like system RAM or CPU registers or cache.
See also: Data at Rest and Data in Transit</description></item><item><title>Data Loss Prevention</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Loss-Prevention/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Loss-Prevention/</guid><description>Keep that data safe Usually an automated tool Can protect [[Intellectual Property]] data Will usually consist of three components Policy Server to configure classification, confidentiality, and privacy rules and polices, log incidents, and compile reports Endpoint Agents to enforce policy on client computers, even when they are not connected to the network Network Agents to scan communications at network borders and interface with web and messaging servers to enforce policy DLP agents scan content in structured formats, like databases with a formal access control model DLP agents can also scan content in unstructured formats, like emails or word processing documents DLP agents can block the transfer of content if it does not conform to a predefined policy (Side note, this is probably what the Pope-blessed laptop used) Remediation The action a DLP software takes when it detects policy violation Alert only Block Quarantine Tombstone The file is quarantined and replaced with one describing the policy violation and how the user can release it again</description></item><item><title>Data Masking</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Masking/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Masking/</guid><description>A Database Deidentification Methods where generic or placeholder labels are substituted for real data while preserving the structure or format of the original data.</description></item><item><title>Data Minimization</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Minimization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Minimization/</guid><description>The principle that data should only be processed and stored if that is necessary to perform the the purpose for which it is collected</description></item><item><title>Data Owner</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Owner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Owner/</guid><description>A senior (executive) role with ultimate responsibility for maintaining the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of the information asset.
See also: Information Life Cycle Management, [[CIA Triad]], Data Controller, and Data Processor</description></item><item><title>Data Privacy Officer</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Privacy-Officer/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Privacy-Officer/</guid><description>Ensures that the processing, disclosure, and retention of PII ([[Personally Identifiable Information]]) complies with legal and regulatory frameworks
See also: Data Roles and Responsibilities and Information Life Cycle Management</description></item><item><title>Data Processor</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Processor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Processor/</guid><description>An entity engaged by the Data Controller to assist with technical collection, storage, or analysis tasks. Follows the instructions of the data controller with regard to collection or processing.</description></item><item><title>Data Retention</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Retention/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Retention/</guid><description>Backing up and archiving information assets to comply with business policies and/or applicable laws and regulations.
Particularly affects financial data and security log data.</description></item><item><title>Data Roles and Responsibilities</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Roles-and-Responsibilities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Roles-and-Responsibilities/</guid><description>A [[data governance]] policy describes the security controls that will be applied to protect data at each stage of its data life cycle.</description></item><item><title>Data Sharing and User Agreement</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Sharing-and-User-Agreement/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Sharing-and-User-Agreement/</guid><description>Personal data can only be collected for a specific purpose A legal means of preventing reidentification of pseudo-anonymized or deidentified data Specifies terms for the way a data set can be analyzed and proscribes the use of reidentification techniques See also: NDA, SLA, ISA, and Purpose Limitation</description></item><item><title>Data Sovereignty</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Sovereignty/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Sovereignty/</guid><description>The idea that a jurisdiction could prevent or restrict processing and storage of data on systems that do not physically reside within that jurisdiction.</description></item><item><title>Data Steward</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Steward/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Steward/</guid><description>Responsible for data quality, which involves tasks like making sure data is labeled and identified correctly with appropriate metadata and that data is collected and stored in a format and with values that comply with applicable laws and regulations.</description></item><item><title>Data Types</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Types/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Data-Types/</guid><description>A data type schema usually applies more detailed labels than Data Classification.
Personally Identifiable Information Data can be used to identify, contact, or locate and individual Several types of PII, including: SSN name date of birth email address telephone number street address biometric data Some information could be PII depending on context.</description></item><item><title>Database Deidentification Methods</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Database-Deidentification-Methods/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Database-Deidentification-Methods/</guid><description>Deidentification methods are usually implemented as part of the database management system hosting the data. Sensitive fields will be tagged for deidentification whenever a query or report is run.</description></item><item><title>Deontology</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Deontology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Deontology/</guid><description>The ethical ideal of logical consistency and duty. To be moral is to do what it is your duty is.</description></item><item><title>Diamond Model</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Diamond-Model/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Diamond-Model/</guid><description> A framework for analyzing cybersecurity events Explores the relationships between adversary, capability, infrastructure, and victim</description></item><item><title>Differential Backups</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Differential-Backups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Differential-Backups/</guid><description>A type of backup where all files modified since the last full backup and all new files are backed up.</description></item><item><title>Digital Forensics</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Digital-Forensics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Digital-Forensics/</guid><description>The practice of collecting evidence from computer systems to a standard that will be accepted in a court of law</description></item><item><title>Discounted Cash Flow</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Discounted-Cash-Flow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Discounted-Cash-Flow/</guid><description>Compares the value of the future worth of the project&amp;rsquo;s expected cash flows to today&amp;rsquo;s dollars, known as present value.</description></item><item><title>Discovery and Concept</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Discovery-and-Concept/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Discovery-and-Concept/</guid><description>The first phase in the Project Life Cycle. This phase determines whether the project is worthwhile. A Business Case is created to document the business need or justification for the project and will often include high0level details about estimated budgets and timelines for completing the project.</description></item><item><title>E-discovery</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/E-discovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/E-discovery/</guid><description>Procedures and tools to collect, preserve, and analyze digital evidence
See Also: Chain of Custody and Digital Forensics</description></item><item><title>Edge Computing</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Edge-Computing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Edge-Computing/</guid><description>Edge computing is devolved from [[Fog Computing]] and uses the following concepts:
Edge devices collect and depend upon data for their operation, like a thermometer in an HVAC system collects temperature data which in turn is used by the HVAC system to turn the heating or air conditioning on or off.</description></item><item><title>Elasticity</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/elasticity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/elasticity/</guid><description>Elasticity is the cloud computing concept of being able to flex resource needs to meet demands. For example, if your ecommerce site is expecting a lot of traffic, you could easily acquire more resources temporarily to accommodate said traffic.</description></item><item><title>Electronic Communications Privacy Act</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Electronic-Communications-Privacy-Act/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Electronic-Communications-Privacy-Act/</guid><description>Deals with three main issues:
The protection of communications while in transfer from sender to receiver The protection of communications held in electronic storage The prohibition of devices from recording, dialing, routing, addressing, and signaling information about a search warrant Passed as an extension of the Wiretap Act</description></item><item><title>Electronic Health Record</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Electronic-Health-Record/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Electronic-Health-Record/</guid><description>A comprehensive view of the patient&amp;rsquo;s complete medical history designed to be shared with authorized providers and staff from more than one organization.</description></item><item><title>Electronic Medical Record</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Electronic-Medical-Record/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Electronic-Medical-Record/</guid><description>A collection of health-related information on an individual that is created, managed, and consulted by authorized clinicians and staff within a single healthcare organizations.</description></item><item><title>Enterprise Resource Planning</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Enterprise-Resource-Planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Enterprise-Resource-Planning/</guid><description>Systems that help companies coordinate their back-office business activities like accounting, procurement, human resources, and more. The idea is that one system provides functionality across the organizational functions and data can be easily shared, compared, and reported on.</description></item><item><title>Enterprise Risk Management</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Enterprise-Risk-Management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Enterprise-Risk-Management/</guid><description>The comprehensive process of evaluating, measuring, and mitigating the many risks that pervade an organization. Often based on frameworks such as NIST&amp;rsquo;s Risk Management Framework or ISO 31K.</description></item><item><title>Equal Accuracy</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Equal-Accuracy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Equal-Accuracy/</guid><description>The outcome where the same percentage of correct judgement is present in all groups</description></item><item><title>Equal Error</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Equal-Error/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Equal-Error/</guid><description>When the proportion of false acceptances is equal to the proportion of false rejections</description></item><item><title>Equal Representation</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Equal-Representation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Equal-Representation/</guid><description>All groups are represented equally</description></item><item><title>Ethics</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Ethics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Ethics/</guid><description>A societal code of behavior, what is generally accepted as &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Ethics in Tech Study Guide</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Ethics-in-Tech-Study-Guide/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Ethics-in-Tech-Study-Guide/</guid><description> Virtue Ethics Deontology Utilitarianism Kantian Ethics Consequentialism Relativism Ethics Morals Corporate Code of Ethics Supply chain sustainability Corporate social responsibility Wiretap Act Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act USA PATRIOT Act General Data Protection Regulation EU Data Protection Directive Electronic Communications Privacy Act Freedom of Information Act American Recovery and Reinvestment Act Fair Credit Reporting Act False Claims Act Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act Communications Decency Act Foreign Corrupt Practices Act Health Information Exchange Electronic Health Record Clinical Decision Support Electronic Medical Record Personal Health Record Misrepresentation Conflict of Interest Bribery Fraud Breach of Contract Protected Attribute Protected Class Statistical Parity Equal Accuracy Equal Representation Equal Error Data Disparity</description></item><item><title>EU Data Protection Directive</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/EU-Data-Protection-Directive/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/EU-Data-Protection-Directive/</guid><description>Requires any company doing business within the borders of the countries comprising the EU to implement a set of privacy directives on the fair and appropriate use of information</description></item><item><title>Executing</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Executing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Executing/</guid><description>The executing phase is where the work of the project is performed and monitored for adherence to the project management plan.</description></item><item><title>Exposure Factor</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Exposure-Factor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Exposure-Factor/</guid><description>The percentage of an asset value that would be lost during a security incident or disaster scenario</description></item><item><title>External Risk</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/External-Risk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/External-Risk/</guid><description>A threat actor from outside an organization represents and external risk. External risks can also exist outside of cybersecurity. Natural disasters are one form of external risk.</description></item><item><title>Fair Credit Reporting Act</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Fair-Credit-Reporting-Act/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Fair-Credit-Reporting-Act/</guid><description>Regulates the operations of credit reporting bureaus, including how they collect, store, and use credit information. Designed to ensure the accuracy, fairness, and privacy of information gathered by the credit reporting companies and to provide guidelines for organizations whose systems that gather and sell information about people.</description></item><item><title>False Claims Act</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/False-Claims-Act/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/False-Claims-Act/</guid><description>AKA the Lincoln Law
Enacted during the US Civil War to combat fraud by companies that sold supplies to the Union Army.</description></item><item><title>Fault Tolerance</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Fault-Tolerance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Fault-Tolerance/</guid><description>Protection against system failure by providing extra (redundant) capacity. Generally, fault tolerant systems identify and eliminate single points of failure.</description></item><item><title>Feasibility Study</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Feasibility-Study/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Feasibility-Study/</guid><description>A study undertaken before the Business Case is written. Can determine whether the project is doable and likely to success. Examines the viability of the product, service, or result of the project.</description></item><item><title>Financial and Performance Analysis</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Financial-and-Performance-Analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Financial-and-Performance-Analysis/</guid><description>A means to compare the benefits obtained from project requests by evaluating them using the same criteria. There are several financial and performance methods that evaluate benefits and rewards, such as :</description></item><item><title>Financial Information</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Financial-Information/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Financial-Information/</guid><description>Data held about bank and investment accounts, plus information such as payroll and tax returns. All about the money. Payment card information falls under financial information as well</description></item><item><title>Fog Computing</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Fog-Computing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Fog-Computing/</guid><description>Developed by Cisco, fog computing places fog nodes using Wi-Fi, ZigBee, or 4G/5G to prioritize traffic, analyze and remediate alertable conditions, and backhaul remaining data to the data center for storage and low-priority analysis.</description></item><item><title>Foreign Corrupt Practices Act</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Foreign-Corrupt-Practices-Act/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Foreign-Corrupt-Practices-Act/</guid><description>Makes it a crime to bribe a foreign official, a foreign political part official, or a candidate for foreign political office.</description></item><item><title>Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Foreign-Intelligence-Surveillance-Act/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Foreign-Intelligence-Surveillance-Act/</guid><description>Describes procedures for the electronic surveillance and collection of foreign intelligence information in communications between foreign governments or agents of foreign governments or foreign organizations.</description></item><item><title>Fraud</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Fraud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Fraud/</guid><description>The crime of obtaining goods, services, or property through deception or trickery</description></item><item><title>Freedom of Information Act</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Freedom-of-Information-Act/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Freedom-of-Information-Act/</guid><description>Grants citizens the right to access certain information and records of federal, state, and local governments upon request. Enables journalists and the public to acquire information that the government is reluctant to release.</description></item><item><title>Full Backups</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Full-Backups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Full-Backups/</guid><description>A type of backup where all selected data is backed up, regardless of when it was previously backed up.</description></item><item><title>General Data Protection Regulation</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/General-Data-Protection-Regulation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/General-Data-Protection-Regulation/</guid><description>Designed to strengthen data protection of individuals within the EU by addressing the export of personal data outside the EU. This allows citizens to see and correct their personal data, and ensure data protection consistency across the EU</description></item><item><title>Geographical Considerations</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Geographical-Considerations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Geographical-Considerations/</guid><description> Storage locations might have to be carefully selected to mitigate Data Sovereignty issues. Most cloud providers allow choice of data centers for processing and storage Employees needing access from multiple geographic locations can apply constraint-based access controls to validate the user&amp;rsquo;s geographic location before authorizing access</description></item><item><title>Government Data</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Government-Data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Government-Data/</guid><description>Complex data collection and processing requirements for internal government agencies.</description></item><item><title>Gramm-Leach-Bliley Act</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Gramm-Leach-Bliley-Act/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Gramm-Leach-Bliley-Act/</guid><description>Governs the collection, disclosure, and protection of consumers&amp;rsquo; nonpublic personal information or Personally Identifiable Information
Companies that offer financial products or services are the ones affected</description></item><item><title>Hashing and Salting</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Hashing-and-Salting/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Hashing-and-Salting/</guid><description>A method of producing a fixed-length string from arbitrary-length plaintext data using an algorithm, like SHA. It should be impossible to match the hash back to a plaintext.</description></item><item><title>Health Information Exchange</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Health-Information-Exchange/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Health-Information-Exchange/</guid><description>The process of sharing patient-level electronic health information between different organizations. The key to electronic exchange is the standardization of health data.</description></item><item><title>Hybrid Cloud</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Hybrid-Cloud/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Hybrid-Cloud/</guid><description>Hybrid clouds utilize on-premises resources combined with off-premises resources. Great for [[notes/Elasticity]] during intermittent busy seasons for smaller companies.</description></item><item><title>Hypervisor</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Hypervisor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Hypervisor/</guid><description>A hypervisor is the system that allows Virtual Machines to be run. There are 2 types of hypervisor: Type 1 and Type 2.</description></item><item><title>Impact</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Impact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Impact/</guid><description>The severity of the risk if realized as s security incident. Could be determined by value of the asset or the cost of disruption if the asset is compromised.</description></item><item><title>Impact Assessments</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Impact-Assessments/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Impact-Assessments/</guid><description>A data protection impact assessment is a process designed to identify the risks of collecting and processing personal data in the context of a business workflow or project and to identify mechanisms that mitigate those risks.</description></item><item><title>Incident Response Exercises</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Incident-Response-Exercises/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Incident-Response-Exercises/</guid><description> 3 main forms Tabletop Least costly Facilitator presents a scenario and the responders explain what action they would take Does not use computer systems Usually uses flashcards Walkthroughs Facilitator present a scenario, like in tabletop Responders demonstrate rather than explain what actions they would take Simulations Most costly Red team attempts and intrusion while blue team operates response and recovery controls White team moderates and evaluates the exercise</description></item><item><title>Incident Response Plan</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Incident-Response-Plan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Incident-Response-Plan/</guid><description>Incident Response Plan Lists the procedures, contacts, and resources available to responders for various incident categories CIRT responsible for developing profiles or scenarios of typical incidents (DDoS, virus/worm outbreak, data exfiltration by an external adversary, etc) These profiles guide investigators in determining priorities and remediation plans [[CIRT]] could also be responsible for making a [[Playbook]] Assess for Severity Each incident has to be assessed and prioritized to allocate resources efficiently.</description></item><item><title>Incident Response Process</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Incident-Response-Process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Incident-Response-Process/</guid><description>Defined by NIST 800.61r2, incident response follows a well-structure process. There are 6 principal stages in an incident response lifecycle.</description></item><item><title>Incremental Backups</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Incremental-Backups/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Incremental-Backups/</guid><description>A type of backup where only files modified since the last backup and new files are backed up.</description></item><item><title>Information Life Cycle Management</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Information-Life-Cycle-Management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Information-Life-Cycle-Management/</guid><description>The information life cycle model Creation/collection data may be generated by an employee or automated system, or it may be submitted by a customer or supplier.</description></item><item><title>Initiating</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Initiating/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Initiating/</guid><description>The formal authorization for a new project to begin or for an existing project to continue into the next phase. This phase includes all the activities that lead up to the final authorization to begin the project.</description></item><item><title>Intellectual Property</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Intellectual-Property/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Intellectual-Property/</guid><description>Information created and owned by the company, usually about products or services they perform Also known as Proprietary Information Obvious target for a company&amp;rsquo;s competitors May represent a counterfeiting opportunity, like movies, music, and books See also: Personal Data, Sensitive Data, and Data Classifications</description></item><item><title>Intellectual Property Theft</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Intellectual-Property-Theft/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Intellectual-Property-Theft/</guid><description>The exfiltration of Intellectual Property. Stolen IP data loses much of its commercial value. Difficult to recover losses.
See also: Risk Management and Enterprise Risk Management</description></item><item><title>Internal Rate of Return</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Internal-Rate-of-Return/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Internal-Rate-of-Return/</guid><description>The discount rate when the present value of the cash inflows equals the original investment. IRR states the profitability of an investment as an average percent over the life of the investment.</description></item><item><title>Internal Risk</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Internal-Risk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Internal-Risk/</guid><description>Threats that can occur from inside the organization. Not always malicious. Includes contractors who were granted temp access.
See also: Risk Management and Enterprise Risk Management</description></item><item><title>ISA</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/ISA/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/ISA/</guid><description>Interconnection Security Agreement
Defined by NIST&amp;rsquo;s SP800-47 &amp;ldquo;Managing the Security of Information Exchanges&amp;rdquo;. Any federal agency interconnecting its IT system to a third party must create and ISA to govern the relationship</description></item><item><title>Kantian Ethics</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Kantian-Ethics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Kantian-Ethics/</guid><description>See Deontology</description></item><item><title>Likelihood</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Likelihood/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Likelihood/</guid><description>The probability of a threat being realized
See also: Impact</description></item><item><title>Misrepresentation</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Misrepresentation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Misrepresentation/</guid><description>The misstatement or incomplete statement of material fact. If the misrepresentation causes the other party to enter into a contract, that party may have the legal right to cancel the contract or seek reimbursement for damages</description></item><item><title>MITRE ATT&amp;CK</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/MITRE-ATTCK/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/MITRE-ATTCK/</guid><description>MITRE Corporation&amp;rsquo;s Adversarial Tactics, Techniques, and Common Knowledge
A matrices of known TTPs Free at ( http://attack.mitre.org) Tags each technique with a unique ID and categorizes it by tactic Doesn&amp;rsquo;t assume how any adversary will run a campaign</description></item><item><title>Morals</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Morals/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Morals/</guid><description>Morals are personal principals, what guides you as an individual to what is &amp;ldquo;right&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Multiparty Risk</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Multiparty-Risk/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Multiparty-Risk/</guid><description>An adverse event that impacts multiple organizations. Typically arise from supplier relationships. Also referred to as ripple impacts.
See also: Risk Management and Enterprise Risk Management</description></item><item><title>Multiprocessing</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Multiprocessing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Multiprocessing/</guid><description>The running of two or more programs or sequences of instructions simultaneously by a computer with more than one CPU</description></item><item><title>NDA</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/NDA/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/NDA/</guid><description>Non-disclosure agreement
Legal basis for protecting information assets Used between companies and employees, between companies and contractors, and between two companies If agreement is broken, there may be legal consequences Deter employees and contractors from violating the trust that an employer places in them See also: ISA, SLA, Data Sharing and User Agreement</description></item><item><title>Net Present Value</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Net-Present-Value/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Net-Present-Value/</guid><description>A cash flow technique that takes into account the differences in the value of money over time by calculating the revenues or cash flows the organization expects to receive over the life of the project in today&amp;rsquo;s dollars.</description></item><item><title>Operations</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Operations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Operations/</guid><description>Operations are ongoing and repetitive, unlike Projects that have start and end dates. Operations typically involve ongoing functions that support the production of goods and services.</description></item><item><title>Order of Restoration</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Order-of-Restoration/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Order-of-Restoration/</guid><description> Enable and test power delivery systems Enable and test switch infrastructure, then routing appliance and systems Enable and test network security appliances Enable and test critical network servers Enable and test back-end and middleware, and then verify data integrity Enable and test front-end applications Enable client workstations and devices and client browser access</description></item><item><title>Payback Period</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Payback-Period/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Payback-Period/</guid><description>A cash flow technique that identifies the length of time it takes for the organization to recover all the costs of producing the project.</description></item><item><title>PCI DSS</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/PCI-DSS/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/PCI-DSS/</guid><description>Payment Card Industry Data Security Standard
defines the safe handling and storage of Financial Information</description></item><item><title>Personal Data</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Personal-Data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Personal-Data/</guid><description>Information that relates to an individual identity
See also Proprietary Information, Sensitive Data, and Data Classifications</description></item><item><title>Personal Health Information</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Personal-Health-Information/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Personal-Health-Information/</guid><description>Sensitive Data involving medical records, hospital results, insurance information, etc.</description></item><item><title>Personal Health Record</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Personal-Health-Record/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Personal-Health-Record/</guid><description>Includes the portions of the Electronic Health Record that are routinely shared with the patient, such as personal identifiers, contact information, health provider information, problem list, medication history, allergies, immunizations, and lab and test results.</description></item><item><title>Personally Identifiable Information</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Personally-Identifiable-Information/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Personally-Identifiable-Information/</guid><description>Any information that could reasonably identify an individual and must be subjected to regulatory standards. Different standards exist for different types of PII.</description></item><item><title>Planning</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Planning/</guid><description>In the planning phase, the project goals, objectives, and deliverables are refined and broken down into manageable units of work. Project managers create time and cost estimates and determine resource requirements for each activity.</description></item><item><title>Playbook</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Playbook/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Playbook/</guid><description>A checkilst of actions to perform to detect and respond to a specific type of incident</description></item><item><title>Portfolios</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Portfolios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Portfolios/</guid><description>A collection of Programs, sub-portfolios, and Projects that support strategic business goals or objectives. Unlike programs, portfolios may consist of projects that are not related</description></item><item><title>Privacy Notices</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Privacy-Notices/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Privacy-Notices/</guid><description>Personal data cannot be collected, processed, or retained without the individual&amp;rsquo;s informed consent.
Privacy notices are a consent statement that lists the stated purpose for the collection and processing of data in plain language.</description></item><item><title>Privacy vs Security</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Privacy-vs-Security/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Privacy-vs-Security/</guid><description>Privacy Privacy requires that private data is identified, stored, processed, and retained in a way that is compliant with relevant regulations.</description></item><item><title>Program</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Program/</guid><description>A group of related Projects that are managed together using coordinated processes and techniques
See also: Portfolios</description></item><item><title>Project</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Project/</guid><description>A project can be anything as long as it fits the following criteria:
A project must be Unique. Every project involves doing something new, which means the end result should be a unique product or service Temporary: Projects must have defined start and end dates.</description></item><item><title>Project Life Cycle</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Project-Life-Cycle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Project-Life-Cycle/</guid><description>Project management is performed in a series of phases that are executed to apply knowledge, skills, tools, and techniques to the project activities to meet the project requirements.</description></item><item><title>Projects and Opperations</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Projects-and-Opperations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Projects-and-Opperations/</guid><description>Projects come about to meet a specific, unique result. Once a project is completed, it is often handed off to Operations to manage the everyday tasks that the project implemented.</description></item><item><title>Proprietary Information</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Proprietary-Information/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Proprietary-Information/</guid><description>Information created and owned by the company, usually about products or services they perform Also known as Intellectual Property (IP) Obvious target for a company&amp;rsquo;s competitors May represent a counterfeiting opportunity, like movies, music, and books See also: Personal Data, Sensitive Data, and Data Classifications</description></item><item><title>Protected Attribute</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Protected-Attribute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Protected-Attribute/</guid><description>Qualities, traits, or characteristics that, by law, cannot be discriminated against</description></item><item><title>Protected Class</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Protected-Class/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Protected-Class/</guid><description>Groups of people who are legally protected from being harmed or harrassed by laws, practices, or policies.</description></item><item><title>Purpose Limitation</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Purpose-Limitation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Purpose-Limitation/</guid><description>The principle that personal information can be collected and processed only for a stated purpose to which the subject has consented.</description></item><item><title>Qualitative Risk Assessment</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Qualitative-Risk-Assessment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Qualitative-Risk-Assessment/</guid><description>Focused on identifying significant risk factors. Based off of opinions of which risk factors are significant rather than calculations, like in Quantitative Risk Assessment.</description></item><item><title>Quantitative Risk Assessment</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Quantitative-Risk-Assessment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Quantitative-Risk-Assessment/</guid><description>A form of risk assessment that aims to assign concrete values to each risk factor. Determining and assigning these values is complex and time consuming.</description></item><item><title>Qui Tam</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Qui-Tam/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Qui-Tam/</guid><description>A provision in the False Claims Act that allows a citizen to sue for fraud on behalf of the government</description></item><item><title>Redundancy</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Redundancy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Redundancy/</guid><description>Overprovisioning resources at the component, host, and/or site level so that there is failover to a working instance in the event of a problem</description></item><item><title>Relativism</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Relativism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Relativism/</guid><description>The idea that all norms and values are relative to the circumstances surrounding them
See also: Virtue Ethics</description></item><item><title>Return On Investment</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Return-On-Investment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Return-On-Investment/</guid><description>Measures the profitability of an investment and is often used to compare one investment to another. It measures the expected returns of the investment as compared to its costs and is displayed as a percentage.</description></item><item><title>Risk and Control Assessment</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Risk-and-Control-Assessment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Risk-and-Control-Assessment/</guid><description>An external process to identify risks and the effectiveness with which controls mitigate those risks. Often performed through questionnaires and workshops with department managers.</description></item><item><title>Risk and Control Self-Assessment</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Risk-and-Control-Self-Assessment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Risk-and-Control-Self-Assessment/</guid><description>An internal process undertaken by stakeholders to identify risks and the effectiveness with which controls mitigate those risks. Often performed through questionnaires and workshops with department managers/ The outcome of an RCSA is a report.</description></item><item><title>Risk Avoidance</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Risk-Avoidance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Risk-Avoidance/</guid><description>The practice of stopping an activity that is risk-bearing.
See Also: Risk Transference and Risk Management</description></item><item><title>Risk Management</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Risk-Management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Risk-Management/</guid><description>Risk management is the process for identifying, assessing, and mitigation vulnerabilities and threats to the essential functions that a business must perform to serve its customers There are 5 main phases to risk management:</description></item><item><title>Risk Mitigation</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Risk-Mitigation/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Risk-Mitigation/</guid><description>The overall process of reducing exposure to or the effects of risk factors.
See also: Risk Management</description></item><item><title>Risk Transference</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Risk-Transference/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Risk-Transference/</guid><description>Risk transference is the idea that utilizing cloud computing allows a company to transfer some degree of risk to another party.</description></item><item><title>Scalability</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Scalability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Scalability/</guid><description>The ability to add more resources in parallel with existing resources or increase the power of existing resources
See also: Elasticity</description></item><item><title>Scoring Model</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Scoring-Model/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Scoring-Model/</guid><description>A scoring model has a predefined list of criteria against which each alternative solution or project is rated. Each criterion is given both a scoring range and a weighting factor.</description></item><item><title>Sensitive Data</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Sensitive-Data/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Sensitive-Data/</guid><description> Typically used in context of Personal Data in which information about a subject could harm them if made public and could prejudice decisions made about the subject Defined by the GDPR, sensitive data includes: religious beliefs political opinions trade union membership gender sexual orientation racial or ethnic origin genetic data health information</description></item><item><title>Single Loss Expectancy</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Single-Loss-Expectancy/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Single-Loss-Expectancy/</guid><description>The amount that would be lost in a single occurrence of the risk factor. This is determined by multiplying the value of the asset by an Exposure Factor</description></item><item><title>SLA</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/SLA/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/SLA/</guid><description>Service Level Agreement
A contractual agreement setting out the detailed terms under which a service is provided. Can include terms for security access controls and risk assessments, plus processing requirement for confidential and private data</description></item><item><title>Software Design Lifecycle</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Software-Development-Lifecycle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Software-Development-Lifecycle/</guid><description>There are 4 main phases to the software development lifecycle:
Analysis This is the practice of determining the goals for a program The &amp;ldquo;Why&amp;rdquo; Design Design determines the specifics of how to build a program The &amp;ldquo;What&amp;rdquo; Implementation Implementation builds the program according to the design The &amp;ldquo;How&amp;rdquo; Testing Testing checks that the program meets the goal There are 2 main methods of implementing the software development lifecycle: the [[notes/Waterfall Approach]] and the [[notes/Agile Approach]].</description></item><item><title>Stakeholders</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Stakeholders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Stakeholders/</guid><description>Anyone who has a vested interest in the project. Can include individuals and organizations, and both the project sponsor and the project manager are considered stakeholders.</description></item><item><title>Statistical Parity</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Statistical-Parity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Statistical-Parity/</guid><description>A natural way to model equity: members of each group have the same chance or receiving the favorable output</description></item><item><title>Supply chain sustainability</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Supply-chain-sustainability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Supply-chain-sustainability/</guid><description>A component of Corporate social responsibility that focuses on developing and maintaining a supply chain that meets the needs of the present without compromising the ability of future generations to meet their needs</description></item><item><title>Threat</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Threat/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Threat/</guid><description>A potential negative action or event that utilizes a Vulnerability to cause harm to a system. Not always malicious</description></item><item><title>Tokenization</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Tokenization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Tokenization/</guid><description>Database Deidentification Methods where a unique token is substituted for data.</description></item><item><title>USA PATRIOT Act</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/USA-PATRIOT-Act/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/USA-PATRIOT-Act/</guid><description>Passed after 9/11, it gave sweeping new powers to both domestic law enforcement and U.S. international intelligence agency, including increasing the ability of law enforcement agencies to search telephone, email, medical, financial, and other records.</description></item><item><title>Utilitarianism</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Utilitarianism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Utilitarianism/</guid><description>Jeremy Bentham believed that a moral action is one that produces the most pleasure for everyone concerned.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Desktop</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Virtual-Desktop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Virtual-Desktop/</guid><description>Virtual desktops are essentially hosted VMs that a client connects to for OS access. The clients are typically not very resource-equipped and are referred to as &amp;ldquo;thin clients.</description></item><item><title>Virtual Machines</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Virtual-Machines/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Virtual-Machines/</guid><description>A way to virtualize desktops for many different purposes. Virtual Machines (VMs) can be implemented to run software with other OS dependencies, as a means of sandboxing for security purposes, for training, or for thin client and [[Virtual Desktop]] environments.</description></item><item><title>Virtue Ethics</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Virtue-Ethics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Virtue-Ethics/</guid><description>Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s philosophy that the ethical thing to do is dependent on the context of the decision required. It prioritizes &amp;ldquo;fitting in&amp;rdquo; to society rather than what is morally correct for the individual</description></item><item><title>Vulnerabilities</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Vulnerability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Vulnerability/</guid><description>A weakness in an IT system that can be exploited by a threat actor
See also: Threat</description></item><item><title>Waterfall Approach</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Waterfall-Approach/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Waterfall-Approach/</guid><description>The Software Development Lifecycle approach that involves delivering the project all at once. Categorized by longer development time, this approach is relatively rigid and aims to deliver the final product all at once.</description></item><item><title>Wiretap Act</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Wiretap-Act/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Wiretap-Act/</guid><description>AKA Title III of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act, this act regulates the interception of wire and oral communications.</description></item></channel></rss>