<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>project on</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/tags/project/</link><description>Recent content in project on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://garden.nategb.com/tags/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Architect</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Architect/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Architect/</guid><description>Umbrella term for many designer roles in an organization. Architects design solutions and ensure different systems work together to adhere to solution requirements</description></item><item><title>Business Analyst</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Business-Analyst/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Business-Analyst/</guid><description>Business analysts improve the final product. BAs hold a unique role between business and technical teams. They deeply understand the business direction and company priorities and are familiar with the software environment.</description></item><item><title>Business Case</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Business-Case/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Business-Case/</guid><description>A written document or report that helps executive management and key stakeholders determine the benefits and rewards of the Project. The elements of a Business Case include:</description></item><item><title>Cash Flow Techniques</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Cash-Flow-Techniques/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Cash-Flow-Techniques/</guid><description>Provide data on the overall financials of the alternative solutions or projects. Each of these techniques rely on the concept of time value of money.</description></item><item><title>Closing</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Closing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Closing/</guid><description>The primary purpose of the closing phase is to validate deliverables and document the formal acceptance of the project work. Once that&amp;rsquo;s complete, a handoff occurs whereby the completed product or result of the project is turned over to the organization for ongoing maintenance and support.</description></item><item><title>Cost-Benefit Analysis</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Cost-Benefit-Analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Cost-Benefit-Analysis/</guid><description>Compares the cost to produce the product or service to the financial gain (or benefit) the organization stands to make as a result of executing the project.</description></item><item><title>Customer Relationship Management</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Customer-Relationship-Management/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Customer-Relationship-Management/</guid><description>Software that helps businesses manage their relationships and interactions with their customers and future customers. CRMs aggregate data about the customer in one place and provide an efficient and practical way for the organization to interact with their customer.</description></item><item><title>Developers</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Developers/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Developers/</guid><description>The reaming Scrum team members that aren&amp;rsquo;t the Scrum Master or Product Owner. They are not limited to software developers. Developer is basically short for &amp;ldquo;Scrum Team Member&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Discounted Cash Flow</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Discounted-Cash-Flow/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Discounted-Cash-Flow/</guid><description>Compares the value of the future worth of the project&amp;rsquo;s expected cash flows to today&amp;rsquo;s dollars, known as present value.</description></item><item><title>Discovery and Concept</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Discovery-and-Concept/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Discovery-and-Concept/</guid><description>The first phase in the Project Life Cycle. This phase determines whether the project is worthwhile. A Business Case is created to document the business need or justification for the project and will often include high0level details about estimated budgets and timelines for completing the project.</description></item><item><title>Enterprise Resource Planning</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Enterprise-Resource-Planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Enterprise-Resource-Planning/</guid><description>Systems that help companies coordinate their back-office business activities like accounting, procurement, human resources, and more. The idea is that one system provides functionality across the organizational functions and data can be easily shared, compared, and reported on.</description></item><item><title>Executing</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Executing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Executing/</guid><description>The executing phase is where the work of the project is performed and monitored for adherence to the project management plan.</description></item><item><title>Extreme Programming</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Extreme-Programming/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Extreme-Programming/</guid><description>What is it? An Agile Approach for software development Heavy emphasis on software engineering practices XP takes good software development practices to extreme levels and codifies them Puts a customer on the development team Aims to create a higher quality of life for the developer and better software for the customer 5 values Communication Simplicity Feedback Respect Courage Roles Customer Decides which features are needed eventually and which are needed next Teams can select one of more customer proxies if the &amp;ldquo;customer&amp;rdquo; is a large user-base Tracker Captures metrics, measures progress, and looks for improvement opportunities Usually part-time role for a team member Coach Mentors team members on how to use XP practices.</description></item><item><title>Feasibility Study</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Feasibility-Study/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Feasibility-Study/</guid><description>A study undertaken before the Business Case is written. Can determine whether the project is doable and likely to success. Examines the viability of the product, service, or result of the project.</description></item><item><title>Financial and Performance Analysis</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Financial-and-Performance-Analysis/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Financial-and-Performance-Analysis/</guid><description>A means to compare the benefits obtained from project requests by evaluating them using the same criteria. There are several financial and performance methods that evaluate benefits and rewards, such as :</description></item><item><title>Functional Organization</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Functional-Organization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Functional-Organization/</guid><description>An Organizational Structure by areas of expertise or specialization. Basic departmental structure.</description></item><item><title>Increment</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Increment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Increment/</guid><description>A complete body of work that meets the definition of done and moves toward the Product Goal</description></item><item><title>Initiating</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Initiating/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Initiating/</guid><description>The formal authorization for a new project to begin or for an existing project to continue into the next phase. This phase includes all the activities that lead up to the final authorization to begin the project.</description></item><item><title>Internal Rate of Return</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Internal-Rate-of-Return/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Internal-Rate-of-Return/</guid><description>The discount rate when the present value of the cash inflows equals the original investment. IRR states the profitability of an investment as an average percent over the life of the investment.</description></item><item><title>Kanban</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Kanban/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Kanban/</guid><description>What is it? An Agile Approach framework that is relatively new Originally used in lean manufacturing in the 1940s to control inventory and manage workflow, it eventually made it into software development Today we use Kanban to control work in progress levels and manage workflows in software and other business processes.</description></item><item><title>Matrix Organization</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Matrix-Organization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Matrix-Organization/</guid><description>And Organizational Structure that includes functional leaders and specialized roles, while also including project managers. When a project forms, team members from the functional areas work on the project teams, either part-time or full-time.</description></item><item><title>Net Present Value</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Net-Present-Value/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Net-Present-Value/</guid><description>A cash flow technique that takes into account the differences in the value of money over time by calculating the revenues or cash flows the organization expects to receive over the life of the project in today&amp;rsquo;s dollars.</description></item><item><title>Operations</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Operations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Operations/</guid><description>Operations are ongoing and repetitive, unlike Projects that have start and end dates. Operations typically involve ongoing functions that support the production of goods and services.</description></item><item><title>Organizational Structures</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Organizational-Structures/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Organizational-Structures/</guid><description>Three main types of organization structures:
Functional Organization Projectized Organization Matrix Organization Project managers have no power in a functional org, while they have all the power in a projectized org.</description></item><item><title>Payback Period</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Payback-Period/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Payback-Period/</guid><description>A cash flow technique that identifies the length of time it takes for the organization to recover all the costs of producing the project.</description></item><item><title>Planning</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Planning/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Planning/</guid><description>In the planning phase, the project goals, objectives, and deliverables are refined and broken down into manageable units of work. Project managers create time and cost estimates and determine resource requirements for each activity.</description></item><item><title>Portfolios</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Portfolios/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Portfolios/</guid><description>A collection of Programs, sub-portfolios, and Projects that support strategic business goals or objectives. Unlike programs, portfolios may consist of projects that are not related</description></item><item><title>Product Backlog</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Product-Backlog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Product-Backlog/</guid><description>An ordered list of product changes or enhancements. The Product Owner owns and manages the backlog. However, the Scrum Team helps refine the top product backlog items so that they can begin to implement them.</description></item><item><title>Product Goal</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Product-Goal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Product-Goal/</guid><description>A long-term goal of an agile product</description></item><item><title>Product Owner</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Product-Owner/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Product-Owner/</guid><description>Each Scrum Team needs a product owner, but they can serve on multiple agile teams. The product owner creates, maintains, and owns the Product Backlog.</description></item><item><title>Program</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Program/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Program/</guid><description>A group of related Projects that are managed together using coordinated processes and techniques
See also: Portfolios</description></item><item><title>Project</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Project/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Project/</guid><description>A project can be anything as long as it fits the following criteria:
A project must be Unique. Every project involves doing something new, which means the end result should be a unique product or service Temporary: Projects must have defined start and end dates.</description></item><item><title>Project Life Cycle</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Project-Life-Cycle/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Project-Life-Cycle/</guid><description>Project management is performed in a series of phases that are executed to apply knowledge, skills, tools, and techniques to the project activities to meet the project requirements.</description></item><item><title>Project Manager</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Project-Manager/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Project-Manager/</guid><description>Owns day-to-day project management responsibilities. Accountable to the project sponsor.
Responsibilities include:
Build the project team and secure necessary resources Build the project charter and define the project scope Establish the required project logs and processes, including the issue log, change log, and risk register Ensure the project deliverables are met Prepare and deliver project status updates Track the project&amp;rsquo;s progress and status Manage vendor performance and relationships See also: Business Analyst</description></item><item><title>Projectized Organization</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Projectized-Organization/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Projectized-Organization/</guid><description>An Organizational Structure that pools resources around projects. A project manager leads a group of people as long as a project exists.</description></item><item><title>Projects and Opperations</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Projects-and-Opperations/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Projects-and-Opperations/</guid><description>Projects come about to meet a specific, unique result. Once a project is completed, it is often handed off to Operations to manage the everyday tasks that the project implemented.</description></item><item><title>Quality Assurance</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Quality-Assurance/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Quality-Assurance/</guid><description>Help ensure code quality. Work with Developers
Responsibilities include:
Write tests against requirements Run tests on completed code to find defects and bugs</description></item><item><title>Return On Investment</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Return-On-Investment/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Return-On-Investment/</guid><description>Measures the profitability of an investment and is often used to compare one investment to another. It measures the expected returns of the investment as compared to its costs and is displayed as a percentage.</description></item><item><title>Scoring Model</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Scoring-Model/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Scoring-Model/</guid><description>A scoring model has a predefined list of criteria against which each alternative solution or project is rated. Each criterion is given both a scoring range and a weighting factor.</description></item><item><title>Scrum</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Scrum/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Scrum/</guid><description>A lightweight, customer-centric framework. Arguably the most common Agile Approach framework.
All or nothing framework: you use every part of scrum or it isn&amp;rsquo;t scrum 5 Scrum values describe how people should approach each other Commitment Focus Openness Respect Courage 3 Scrum Pillars represent how teams should treat the work Transparency Inspections Adaptation The 4 steps of Scrum are: Product owner prioritizes work into a product backlog Scrum team selects the top items in the backlog.</description></item><item><title>Scrum Master</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Scrum-Master/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Scrum-Master/</guid><description>The agile team&amp;rsquo;s Scrum coach. They help the Scrum Team, Product Owner, and organization improve how they apply Scrum. NOT a Project Manager!</description></item><item><title>Scrum Team</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Scrum-Team/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Scrum-Team/</guid><description>The group of people who work together to deliver increments of value. Includes one Scrum Master, one Product Owner, and Developers.</description></item><item><title>Sprint</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Sprint/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Sprint/</guid><description>A Scrum iteration and the container for all other Scrum events. Sprints are fixed lengths, usually one week to one month.</description></item><item><title>Sprint Backlog</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Sprint-Backlog/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Sprint-Backlog/</guid><description>The Scrum Team&amp;rsquo;s plan for the upcoming sprint. It includes what the team will do, why they think it is important, and how they will get it done.</description></item><item><title>Sprint Goal</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Sprint-Goal/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Sprint-Goal/</guid><description>The primary value that a team plans to deliver in a given sprint</description></item><item><title>Stakeholders</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Stakeholders/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Stakeholders/</guid><description>Anyone who has a vested interest in the project. Can include individuals and organizations, and both the project sponsor and the project manager are considered stakeholders.</description></item><item><title>Subject Matter Expert</title><link>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Subject-Matter-Expert/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://garden.nategb.com/notes/Subject-Matter-Expert/</guid><description>A general label for anybody who is a respected expert in their field</description></item></channel></rss>